Benjamin Malley

(734) 277 2820 benjamin.malley@gmail.com benjaminmalley.github.com/about

I am a software developer and user experience professional with over five years of experience researching, managing and implementing software solutions to solve business problems. I am comfortable with a variety of tools and technologies for both web and mobile development.

EDUCATION

University of Michigan, MS in Information – Human-Computer Interaction (April 2010) President, School of Information Student Association (2009 – 2010) Member, Provost's Student Academic Advisory Board (2009 – 2010)

Warren Wilson College, BA in Mathematics (May 2005)

SKILLS

Software development

Agile development

Python (Django, Flask) JavaScript (jQuery, d3, Angular) Haskell Java (Android SDK)

Databases
(MySQL, MongoDB

(MySQL, MongoDB, Redis) HTML5 & CSS (Bootstrap) Version control (git)

Design methods

Wireframing /
Prototyping
User research /
Contextual inquiry
Survey design
Usability testing

Data analysis

Applied statistics & machine learning Information visualization Social network analysis R (ggplot2, igraph) Python (numpy, scipy) Web analytics (Google analytics)

EXPERIENCE

Analyst, Altarum Institute (May 2011 – Present)

I advise clients on the workflow impact, user experience and population-level health outcomes of health information systems and build new systems to address these needs.

I am currently designing a clinical decision support system to empower physicians and reduce patient demand for inappropriate medicine. I am directly responsible for user research, prototyping and front-end development (using Bootstrap and Angular).

I led the development of an \$8.5 million, <u>3-year program to reduce inappropriate imaging</u> in Michigan's largest provider organizations, managing a five-person team in conducting research, developing a business case and operations plan, and establishing partnerships with clinical leaders.

Research Intern, Adobe Creative Technologies Lab (June 2010 - September 2010)

To identify and solve problems faced by users of Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator, I designed and led a user study and analyzed data from Adobe.com. I provided usability and user experience analysis to product leads for Photoshop and collaborated on the design of Photoshop with Friends, a social learning tool.

Co-founder, Phonagle LLC (April 2009 – June 2010)

As part of a four-person team, I developed <u>outWord</u>, a location-based word game for the iPhone with more than 10,000 downloads. We won the 2009 RPM Ventures business competition (\$20,000 award), competing against more than 35 startups. I was responsible for both front end code in Objective-C and server-side code using Python's Django framework.

Associate, PricewaterhouseCoopers (May 2006 – June 2008)

To support business IT objectives, I performed systems analysis, evaluation of vendor solutions and user testing for the implementation of new data and infrastructure management systems.

Web Developer, University of Michigan (July 2005 – April 2006)

I designed a new web portal for a research department using JavaScript, HTML and CSS.

SELECTED PROJECTS

en route

I designed and developed a mobile <u>web application</u> that allows users to share their location during a trip, for example when picking someone up from the airport. To iterate on the design, I developed and conducted user studies on wireframes and functional prototypes.

Feedback channels: real-time feedback for the classroom (class project)

As part of a five-person team, I designed a <u>web application</u> that allows students to give feedback and ask questions during lectures without interrupting class. We incorporated surveys, <u>personas and scenarios</u> and user studies into our design.

Photoshop with Friends: A Synchronous Learning Community for Graphic Design. Juho Kim, Benjamin Malley, Joel Brandt, Mira Dontcheva, Diana Joseph, Krzysztof Z. Gajos, and Robert C. Miller. CSCW 2012 Interactive Demo, Seattle, USA 2012.

I was a contributor to a system designed mitigate the difficulties encountered when searching the web for help with graphic design tasks by providing just-in-time context-aware help.

Haskell statistics (open source contribution)

I contributed code to the Haskell statistics library to efficiently compute probability distributions.